### HAMMAD IJAZ **CHAUDHRY**

### INTERNATIONAL RELATIONING & MARKEING PROFESSIONAL

### **ABOUT ME**

Carrying a combined skillset in Business Development, Account Management and Client Services, my experience in the international business and customer service come with a growth and development by identifying new business opportunities, new distribution channels and influencing and negotiating with decision-makers at all levels.

Specializing in growing sector and vertical-specific markets with a proven track record of creating and executing go-to-market strategies, driving incremental growth within existing customer portfolios and cultivating

### CONTACT

Lahore-Pakistan +92 321 4388843 hammadijazchaudhry@gmail.com

#### **EDUCATION**

2001 – 2003	•	Masters in Business Administration Premier College of Business Administration Lahore – Pakistan
1999 – 2001		Bachelors in Business Administration Premier College of Business Administration Lahore – Pakistan
1997 – 1999		Intermediate in General Sciences Government College Lahore – Pakistan
1985 – 1996 <b>EXPERIENCE</b>		Schooling Aitchison College Lahore – Pakistan

#### 2022 – JAN 2024 🔎

### **General Manager Import & Export** Venus Pakistan Limited

- Heading the department of import and export of the entire group.
- Looked after the affairs of the import & export in Ras Alkhaimah free zone in UAE, where Venus Pakistan Limited operates by the name of VSF Logistics FZE.
- Supervised operations of the import & export of Gator Trading LLC USA a sister concerned company of Venus Pakistan Limited.
- Dealing with international customers securing orders from new and regular customers.
- Keeping a proper follow up within the company with production and warehouse team. Update the customers with their order status and to make sure that goods are ready at the given time line and are packed as per the requirement of the clients.
- Dealing with international vendors, negotiating rates, terms, placing orders and keep a proper follow-up with the suppliers so that the raw materi als are ready and picked up in time. In liaison with the production units submit projections on yearly and quarterly basis.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### HAMMAD IJAZ CHAUDHRY

## INTERNATIONAL RELATIONING & MARKEING PROFESSIONAL

#### CONTACT

338-E, P.I.A E.C.H.S., Lahore-Pakistan +92 321 4388843 hammadijazchaudhry@gmail.com

- Dealing with the freight forwarders both local and international for Import & Export purpose. Monitor ing closely fluctuation of freight rates. Always tried to get the best rates against the best possible services
- Handling shipments of refrigerated containers up to -22 degree Celsius and dry containers, in both FCL and LCL.
- Supervising export documentation, making sure that all documents including invoice, packing list, certificate of analysis, certificate of origin, phytosanitary certificate, halal certificate, sea and air way bill of lading are as per the require ment of the customers.
- Supervising and checking with the liaison of our clearing team that we should receive all the import documents in proper manner, so that there should be no issue at the time of clear ance of shipment.
- Exploring new market according to the product list of the company, at the same time identify and suggest packing and labelling requirements as per the requirement of the market and client.
- Represented the company in the Gulfood 2023.
   Supervised all the preparation for the show including catalogue, stall designing etc.
- Deal with the Customs Collectorate Mughalpura Dry Port Lahore & IOCO Lahore. Dealing with officials of customs from Inspector to Collector Customs Lahore.
- Handled affairs related to Custom Private Bond of the company and Export Facilitation Scheme "EFS".
- Supervising record keeping of both Private and EFS bonds.

### HAMMAD IJAZ CHAUDHRY

INTERNATIONAL RELATIONING & MARKEING PROFESSIONAL

### **CONTACT**

338-E, P.I.A E.C.H.S., Lahore-Pakistan +92 321 4388843 hammadijazchaudhry@gmail.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

2017 - 2018

## Head of Business Development Raazig International (Pvt.) Ltd.

- Used knowledge of customers, the industry and compeon to idenfy and pursue opportunies for growth.
- Developed the regional strategy to gain new customers in current markets, and to identify ways to penetrate new markets and channels.
- Defined customers and markets which will grow the business and contribute to the success of Raaziq's future.
- Explore new customers and markets, refocusing both core business and new product development to target the greatest opportunities for growth.

2003 - 2017

# General Manager Export & Internal Affairs Pakistan Rug Weavers (Pvt.) Ltd.

- Drive efficiency and effectiveness in all business development and order management activities from initial bid/quotation to final customer satisfaction in the delivery process.
- Monitoring and making of export documentation.
- Dealing with banks form account opening to negotiations of export documents.
- Dealing with freight forwarders assessing their handling of cargo and negotiations rates in the company favour.
- Seeded new markets for our Brands and Products in identified strategic markets.
- Traveled to countries (USA, Europe, South Africa & China) for marketing and sales activities.
- Representing company in the international fairs including the ever popular Carpet Fair "DOMOTEX" in Hanover-Germany.
- Ensure continuous improvement to operational systems, processes and policies in support of business objectives.
- Represented company "PECMA" association of the hand Knotted carpets business